Come on, Nat!
ちょっとナット なんでついてくるのよ
Why are you following me?!
Shut up!
うるせーなー
I'm responsible for the area just above yours, Riko!
俺の担当リコのすぐ上なんだよ
Oh, that's right...
そういえば そうでした
Well, at least help me carry the Relics
on the way home, then.
じゃあ 帰りは遺物運ぶの手伝ってよね
Why?!
なんでだよ
Well, today my haul needs to receive
the highest valuation out of all the Red Whistles!
だって 今日は
赤笛の中で最高の査定額を出さないといけないんだから
Doubt that'll happen.
無理だろ
This area's mostly been searched already...
この辺はもうあらかた探されてるし
and there's not much anything rare left.
珍しい物なんてそうそうねぇよ
だったら 数で勝負よ
That's why it's gonna come down to quantity!
いいのか それで
You okay with that?
How about fudging the numbers...
with that thing you swiped the other day?
あれでごまかしだらどうだ こないだちょろまかしてた
The Star Compass?
星の羅針盤
あれはダメ
I can't do that!
あれはアビスの真実に導いてくれるものなんだから
It guides its user toward the truth of the Abyss, after all.
Besides... if it's found out I was hiding it...
それに もし 隠してたのがバレたら
I'll get a worse punishment
this time than being strung up naked.
今度は裸吊りじゃすまない
Talk about traumatizing a maiden!
乙女のトラウマがぁ
Well, be careful.
まぁ気をつけろよ
Ah, the big gondola.
大ゴンドラ
Huh?!
Wow!
Nat, look at that! It's the 600-meter group!
ナットほらほら 600メートル組だよ
I know, okay?
分かってるよ
Ah, it already went out of sight...
おりゃ もう見えなくなっちゃった
Lucky them... I wish I could ride it.
いいなぁ 乗りだいなぁ
Say... isn't it kinda quiet today?
なぁ なにか今日は静かじゃね
Probably 'cause there aren't any hammerbeaks around...
ツチバシがいないせいじゃない
全然鳴き声聞こえないんもん
I can't hear them singing at all, anyway.
ほんとだ
You're right.
Well, should make it easier to work.
ま やりやすくっていっか
Those guys take anything shiny
back to their nests, after all.
あいつら光ってるの巣に持って帰っちゃうしな
Wait! Why are you going on ahead of me?!
ちょっと 何私より先に行ってるのよ
I'm the one who takes the lead!
先頭は私
Huh?!
I'm gonna go all out excavating today!
今日は もりもり発掘しますよ
そりゃあもう リーダーのぐうの音も出ないほどに
I'll get so much stuff Leader will be at a loss for words!
Alright, let's do this!
I'm gonna get the number one assessment!
さぁ やりますか 査定ナンバーワン
Hup!
There's one!
一つ
二つ
Two!
Three!
三つ
Four...
四つ
Five!
五つ
A skeleton of someone in prayer.
お祈り骸骨
First time I've seen one in quite a while,
so it came as a shock.
久々に見たからビックリしちゃった
お騒がせしてごめんね
Sorry for disturbing you.
I can do it if I just try.
やればできるじゃん 私
これなら600メートルに格上げになるのも時間の問題ね
At this rate, it's only a matter of time
until I'm bumped up to the 600-meter group.
Heavy...
重
Hey, Nat! Help me out!
おい ナット 手伝ってよ
This is seriously heavy. Where'd he run off to...?
マジ重い
どこに行ったのよ ナットの奴
Damn it, Nat.
A crimson splitjaw?
ベニクチナワ
What's it doing this far up?!
なんでこんな浅いとこに
Nat...?!
ナット
Oh no! Is that blood?!
やだ あれ皿
What should I do?
どうしよう ナットが
Nat's...
Nat's gonna be eaten!
ナットが 食べられちゃう
Oh crap!
やばい
M-my arm... is it broken?!
腕が折れて
It's not?!
ない
Nat!
ナット
助けて
Help!
Amazing... The petrified trees are melted.
すごい 化石の樹が溶けてる
I think... maybe somebody saved me.
私 誰かに助けられたのかな
Wow, beautiful...
きれい
H-hello there...
No way! He's not breathing!
うそ 息してない 人工呼吸
He needs artificial respiration!
What's with this texture...?
何この感触
Huh?!
これ 人間じゃない
He's not human!
A-a machine?
き 機械
Wow, this is big!
偉いこっちゃ
Never seen anything like this before!
こんなの見たことない
He's still warm...
まだ あったかい
Must've been moving until a moment ago.
さっきまで動いてたんだ
But, where did this boy come from?
んでもこの子 どこから来たの
The City of the Great Pit
Thanks!
ありがと
Alright! Nat, just a bit more to go!
よし ナットもう少しだよ
Screw you! The hardest part is just starting now!
ばかやろ ここからが一番大変なんだろーが
What's the matter?
どうしたの
Oh, it's just you, Shiggy.
なんだ シギーかよ
You startled me.
びっくりしたぁ
Who's that?
誰
Don't know.
わからない
But, for the time being I'm calling him "robot boy."
けど とりあえず「ロボットくん」
Huh?
I get it. So you swiped something again, Riko, huh?
なるほど またちょろまかすんだリコ
I'm just sheltering him, okay!
匿ってあげるだけよ
Either way is fine by me...
どっちでもいいけどよ
Ah, I knew she'd be there.
やっぱりいた
Director, we're back home now.
院長 ただいま帰りました
Hurry up and get inside.
早く中に入りな
How are we gonna get past her?
あれ どうやって突破するんだ
I think we can manage it.
なんとかなるかも
Huh?!
キユイ
Kiyui!
Huh? Welcome ho-
おかえり
Shh!
He gonna understand that?
あんなんで通じるのか
I hope so...
通じて欲しい
Hm?
Book... book...
本 本
How many times do I need to tell you?!
何度言ったら分かるんだい
Don't read books out on the veranda!
ペランダで本を読むんじゃない
Drop it again and I'll take it away!
今度落としたら没収するからね
Good work out there yesterday.
昨日はご苦労だった
You didn't manage to excavate all that much,
but it was the first time working solo for most of you...
採掘量はそれほどでもなかったが
単独の作業は大半が初めてだ
こんなものだろう
so that's only to be expected.
Once again next week,
来週まだ 同地点
I'll have you base yourselves at the same site
100 meters down and continue working.
100メートルをベースにして 作業を続けてもらう
Those of you who lost their equipment,
file a request with General Affairs.
備品を紛失した者は 総務に申請しろ 以上だ
That is all.
Now, a word from the director.
院長から お話がある
There's just one thing I want to say.
言いたいことは 一つだけだよ
Realize that your possession of a whistle
is based on being a student of the guild's orphanage.
笛持ちは 組合の孤児院生徒である自覚を持って
Strive to work hard...
しっかり稼ぐように
so as not to shame your parents who fell so nobly.
誇り高く散っていった親御さんにも 恥じないようにね
Ah, one more thing.
ああ あともう一つ
That's two things now...
二つ目だ
Helping yourself to Relics is strictly forbidden.
「遺物」のちょろまかしは 御法度だよ
Is she glaring at me?
なんか睨んでる
Relics provide valuable income to the orphanage...
「遺物」は孤児院の大事な稼ぎだ
So pocketing them is inexcusable.
そいつを懐に入れちまうなんて
何をされても文句は言えないよ
No matter the punishment...
I don't want to hear any complaints!
She knows it was me?!
バレてる
次は裸吊りじゃ済まないからね
Next time, it won't stop at just being strung up naked.
Keep that in mind. That is all.
そのつもりで
以上だ
You're dismissed.
解散
She doesn't know... I'm safe.
ばれてない セーフ
リコ
Riko.
ちょっといいか
Can I talk to you for a sec?
Nat tells me he lost his backpack
due to being attacked by a crimson splitjaw...
ナットがリュックを紛失したのは
ベニクチナワに襲われたからだ と言ってるんだが
That's right!
そうなんですよ
If I didn't save him, he'd be snake droppings
right about now. Oh, that Nat!
私が助けながっだら今頃蛇の糞ですよナットのやつ
You saved him?
お前が助けた
Yes! I blew my whistle like so
and made myself a decoy!
はい
この笛でピィーって私が囮になって
Well, how did you get saved, then?
それで お前はどうやって助かったんだ
That's also surprising!
それがもーびっくり
A light like none I've ever seen just-
今まで見たことがない光が
Ah, that was close!
危な
I was just about to start talking about the robot boy...
もう少しでロボット君のことまで喋っちゃうとこだっだ
Well, whatever.
まあいい
Even at a relatively safe 100 meters,
you never know what's going to happen...
比較的安全な深界100メートルでも何が起こるか分からない
From now on, don't let your guard down.
今後は注意を怠るな
Leader!
リーダー
U-um...
あの
お願いがあります
I have a favor to ask!
Please assign me to somewhere deeper!
私の担当をもっと深い所に変えてください
査定で最高額を出したら考えてやると言ったろうが
I thought I told you I'd consider it
if your haul was assessed to be the most valuable!
First, develop some skills that allow you
to cave-raid more efficiently.
まずは 探窟を効率的にこなせる能力を身に付けろ
I... want to quickly build up experience at deeper depths.
私 早く深部の経験を積みたいんです
早く白笛になって
I want to become a White Whistle as soon as I can...
and catch up with my mother!
それでお母さんに追いつきたいんです
お母さんの潜った所まで行って
I'll go down as deep as she has and-
You can't!
ダメだ
To begin with, if you were to go down 400 meters
with your current level of experience,
大体 400メートル潜ったところで
今のお前じゃ行って帰ってくるだけで終わる
simply heading back up again
would be all you could handle!
For the time being, keep your head down and work hard.
しばらくは大人しく働け
Well...
いやぁ
残念だったな 命の恩人くん
That's too bad, Miss Saved-My-Life!
What of it?! Eavesdropping like that isn't cool!
なによ
立ち聞きなんて趣味悪いよ
それより リコ
More importantly, Riko, what are you going to do
about that thing in your room?
お前の部屋のアレどうすんだよ
The robot?
ロボットくん
I'll wake him up, of course.
もちろん起こすよ
He's sleeping? Really?!
寝てんのか あいつ
Yep! We've gotta hurry and wake him!
そっ 早く起こしてあげなきゃ
So, help me out, everybody!
だから みんな協力して
どう どう
So? How's that?
I think maybe he moved a little.
ちょっと動いたかも
Really?!
ほんと
Is someone there?
誰かいるのか
Maybe we should try turning up the power a little bit?
もうちょっと強くしてみたらいいんじゃね
The voices of children?
Maybe we should try turning up the power a little bit?
Yeah, good idea. Riko, set the dial to 2.
そうだね リコ
ダイヤルを「2」に合わせて
ほいきた
I'm on it!
Whatever...
まぁいいや
もう少し眠ろう
I'll sleep... a bit longer...
Done!
So, Shiggy, can I press it now?
ねぇシギー押していい
リコ それ「20」じゃね
Riko, isn't it actually set on 20?
Huh?
H-he's up!
おきた
Seriously?!
まじかぁ
See! I told you that electricity would do the trick!
ほらほら 私の言った通り電気でよかったんだよ
And who was the one who fed him hot coals earlier?
さっき 焼け石炭食わせて他の誰だよ
Hey, hey, Robot Boy, do you recognize me?
ねぇねぇロボットくん
私分かる 君が助けてくれたんだよ
You saved me!
あんな遠くからどうやって蛇をやっつけたの
How did you attack that snake from so far away?
Ah, but first, tell me your name!
でも まずお名前教えて
Hey, don't get carried away! He looks overwhelmed...
おい がっつき過ぎだって
引いてるぞ
Ah, I'm sorry. My name's Riko!
ごめんね 私の名前はリコだよ
I feel bad about replying to a question
with a question, but...
質問を 質問で返すようで悪いが
He spoke!
喋った 可愛い
How cute!
There's something I want to ask...
聞きたい事が
What? What? Ask whatever you want!
なになに なんでも聞いて
Where... is this place?
ここは どこだ
Here?
This is my room! In Belchero Orphanage.
私の部屋よ
ベルチェロ孤児院
Do you guys work as torturers?
君たちは 拷問が仕事なのか
Huh?
Riko's room is actually an old execution chamber.
リコの部屋は元お仕置き部屋なんだ
She got up to too much mischief and was moved here.
悪戯すぎて ここに移されたんだぜ
Anyway, we work as cave raiders.
それから 俺達の仕事は探窟家だ
Well, strictly speaking,
we're apprentices called Red Whistles.
っつっても 見習いの赤笛だけどな
ねぇねぇロボットくん 君の名前は
Hey, hey, Robot Boy, what's your name?
What kind of stuff can you do? Who made you?
どんな機能があるの
君を作ったのはだぁれ
先程から気になってたんだが
It's been on my mind for a bit now, but...
Yeah?
I'm... a robot?
僕は ロボットなのか
You're a robot!
ロボットだよ 電気で動いたし
Electricity made you move!
You totally withstood fire!
火にも強かったし
And there's not a single scratch on you!
肌に傷一つ付かなかったし
あれ ロボって事まで覚えてないの
So, uh... you don't even remember that you're a robot?
Maybe that jolt of electricity messed with his memory?
さっきの電気で記憶飛んでるんじゃね
Everyone, this is bad!
大変だみんな
孤児院の電気 みんな消えちゃってる
The lights are out throughout the whole orphanage!
What?!
I think we overdid it by going full throttle earlier.
出力全開はやりすぎだったかも
早く隠して
Hide quick! Leader is headed straight over here!
リーダーがまっすぐ向かってきてる
Huh?! How does he know it was us?!
なんでバレたの
Probably 'cause you're always pulling stuff.
普段の行いのせいだろ
Can you stand?
立てるか
Suppose we've gotta get that off you first...
それ外さなきゃ無理か
Riko!
リコ
Huh?!
Riko! Distract him best you can!
リコ 上手く誤魔化せよ
I've got a bad feeling...
不安だ
Huh?
Huh?!
Don't come out of there! Got it?
出てぎちゃダメ いい
ひどい目に合わされるよ
We'll be in a world of trouble if you do!
おい リコ 開けろ
Hey, Riko! Open up!
O-okay!
はい
Coming no-!
ただいまぁ
Ow...!
いっつっつっ
So, what the heck did you do this time?
お前 今度は何をした
Huh? Nothing... much really...
何も 大したことは
Ah, m-more importantly, I just banged my foot.
そんなことよりも
足ぶつけたんですよ いい角度で
Caught it at a bad angle, too.
I-it hurts really bad...
ほんと痛くって
I bumped it just the wrong way...
ホントいい角度だったんですよ
Wai...!
Huh?!
So this here is Shiggy's handiwork?
この小細工はシギーだよ
Once again, no idea what he's up to...
また訳の分からんことを
Hey, do you have anything to say for yourself?
おい なんかいうことは
S-sorry. I won't do it again.
ごめんなさい もうしません
探窟がうまく行かなくて焦る気持ちはわかる
I know you're frustrated given that
your cave raiding didn't go so well...
だからと言ってだな
That said, there's simply no sense
in causing a blackout at the orphanage.
孤児院を停電させていい道理はまるでないんだぞ
Riko...?
リコ 聞いてるかリコ
You listening to me, Riko?
Before I hear your explanation for this mess,
この惨状を説明してもらう前に
まずは孤児院の掃除と反省文を書いてもらおうか
I think I'll have you clean the orphanage
and write a sincere apology.
Huh?
Ah... I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい
なるほど
I get it now.
If he was to find me here, there'd be hell to pay...
あれに捕まったら ただではすまんな
Nevertheless, my arm can extend...
それにしても腕が伸びるとは
I've got an extending metal arm...
伸びる金属の腕に この兜
and this helmet...
Talk about suspicious...
いよいよ疑わしいな
What exactly am I?
僕は 何なんだ
Does a robot really need a belly button?
へそとかロボットに必要なのかね
Huh?!
D-do I need this thing, too?
これも必要なのか
Whoa!
Shh!
シギー達が捕まってる隙間に抜け出してきたよ
I took the chance to sneak away
when Shiggy and the others got caught.
Oh, what now? You getting all dressed up
in front of the mirror?
なに なに
鏡の前で おめかし
Uh, n-no...
いや
Riko!
リコ
Riko! Where'd you go?!
リコ どこいった
C-crap!
Riko! Where'd you go?!
やばい
What are we gonna do?! We need to get outta here!
どうしよう 逃げなきゃ
Grab onto me!
僕に捕まって
Quick!
早く
Amazing! What a handy hand!
すごい 便利な手だね
かっこいい
How cool!
Riko, where'd you go?!
リコ どこにいった
Doesn't look like things
are gonna calm down anytime soon.
当分 収まりそうにないぞ
Oh, right!
そうだ 「レグ」に見せたいものがあったんだ
Reg, there's something I've been wanting to show you.
レグ
"Reg"?
君の名前 名前が無いと不便でしょう
That's your name.
Not having one is pretty inconvenient, right?
So what do you think of the name "Reg"?
「レグ」って名前どうかな
構わないが ちなみに由来は
I don't mind it, but... how'd you come up with it, anyway?
It was the name of a dog I used to have.
前に飼ってた犬の名前
犬
A dog...
Reg, hurry, come quick!
レグー 早く早く
We're here!
着いた
もうすぐだからね レグ
It's almost time now, Reg!
Reg, this is the city all of us live in.
レグ これが私達の住む街
大穴の街オースだよ
The city of the great pit. It's called Orth!
オースへようこそ レグ
Welcome to Orth, Reg!
So this pit...?
この穴
Huh?
レグ 「アビス」の事まで忘れちゃったの
Reg, you've even forgotten about the Abyss?!
アビス
"Abyss"?
This great pit is called the Abyss.
この大穴が「アビス」
And I found you down in the Abyss!
君はこのアビスの淵で見つかったんだよ
僕が
I...
I thought that...
私 思ったの
maybe you came up from the bottom of the Abyss, Reg!
レグは「アビス」の厎からやってきたんじゃないかって
Huh?
だって 君みたいなロボット今まで見たことないもん
I mean, I've never seen any kind of robot like you before!
That's gotta be right!
きっとそうだよ
You must've come from the bottom of the Abyss,
which no one has ever seen...
誰も見たことがない「アビス」の厎から
アビス
The Abyss...
About 1,900 years ago,
およそ1900年前 南海ベオルスカの孤島に
a huge pit was discovered on a remote island
in the southern sea of Beoluska.
巨大な縦穴が発見された
With a diameter of around 1,000 meters
and a depth that is still unknown to this day,
直径約1000メートル 深さは今もわかっていない
the mysterious formation mesmerized people.
その不可思議な姿は人々を魅了した
Valuable and dangerous primeval creatures and
mysterious Relics that are beyond comprehension
貴重かつ 危険な原生物たちや
理を超えた不思議な「遺物」が
beckoned adventurers looking to strike it rich,
which in time gave rise to a giant city.
一攫千金を狙う冒険者を呼び寄せ
いつしか そこには巨大な街が築かれた
Over the span of many years,
長年に渡って
with a spirit of adventure for the unknown
and countless legends luring them in,
未知へのロマンと数多の伝説を餌に
the world's only remaining unexplored chasm
has swallowed up a great many people.
多くの人々を飲み込んできた
世界唯一最後の深淵
その名を「アビス」という
It is known as the Abyss.
Everyone, unable to resist, goes down in
Make those eyes shine brighter than a torch
The destination we are aiming for is deep
We squarely lose our way
目指す先は深く まっすぐに迷い込む
The trap of the open-mouthed netherworld
口開けた奈落の罠 真実の跡を追いかけよう
Let's chase the traces of truth
If an answer can be found now, we don't mind losing it all
The echo is still reverberating
So that we do not part with that voice
The compass is always
羅針盤はずっと 闇を指したまま 逃げ場のない 方へ
Pointed to the darkness
Where there is no escape
In that direction
それが呪いでも 鼓動は本物
Even if that is a curse
The pulse is the real thing
二度と憧れは 止まらない
Never again will the yearning stop
Next Episode
Resurrection Festival